Young Master,
公子
I've helped Lieutenant He to settle down.
校尉都已经安顿好了
She won't wake up
无论路途如何颠簸
no matter how bumpy the ride is.
校尉都不会醒过来
Now that we're parting ways,
这一别
I don't know if we'll be able to see each other again.
不知道还能不能
Young Master, it was my pleasure
能陪伴在公子左右多年
to serve you all these years.
是阿恕的福分
Don't be silly.
别那么傻
If Great General does rush inside,
若是大将军真的冲进来
just tell him
你就说
that I forced you to do so.
是我逼你这么做的
You must protect yourself.
你一定要保住
Come and find me
脱身之后
once you've escaped.
再来找我
What sound is that?
这是什么声音
That's the sound of the Cui Army's heavy cavalry.
是崔家军的重骑在冲锋
What kind of heavy cavalry is that?
什么样的重骑
Even the ground is trembling.
竟然大地都震动
That's the reason
那是崔家军
why the Cui Army was known as the Army of Victory.
能号称定胜军的底牌
Nothing can stop
没有什么可以阻挡得了
the Cui Army's heavy cavalry.
崔家军的重骑
No matter who
不论是什么人
or what formation is in front of them,
不论是什么阵法
the Cui Army's heavy cavalry
在崔家军的重骑面前
will trample upon all of them.
都会被踏平的
Ying?
阿萤
Run!
快走
Didn't you hear me?
听到没有
This fellow is still useful to us. Take him with us!
这姓柳的还有用
Ying?
阿萤
you mustn't do this again.
以后可不能再这样了
If you keep this up,
你再这样的话
you'll break my heart.
我的心会疼的
Shiqi!
十七郎
I'm here.
我在 我在
are you real?
真的是你吗
It's me.
是我
Did you know something?
你知道吗
One day,
有一天
I finally managed to escape
我好不容易逃出来
and see you.
看见你
In the end, I realized that it was a dream.
结果发现 那是梦
It wasn't real.
不是真的
You're seeing the real me now.
现在我是真的
Don't believe me? Look.
不信你看
It's true.
是吧
We've gathered
我们把这个方圆百里啊
all the bulls we could find
能找到的牛
within 100 li radius.
统统都给拉过来了
We tied barks
在这个牛肚子上啊
onto their stomach.
绑上树皮
You guys have no idea.
你们不知道啊
When the bulls were charging,
这牛冲起来的时候啊
the ground was trembling.
地动山摇
The people from the mansion
那别苑里的人啊 一看
thought that it was the Cui Army's heavy cavalry.
还真以为是
They were so terrified that they shouted:
吓得一个个都大喊
"The Army of Victory's heavy cavalry is here!"
定胜军的重骑来啦
It was such a magnificent scene.
那场面真是壮观 带劲
What's with your injury then?
那你这伤是怎么回事
Don't mention that.
你就甭提了
When I was charging ahead
当我骑着这牛
with the bull,
冲过去的时候啊
the Jieshuo people
这揭硕人
panicked for some time.
是慌乱了一阵子
But when they saw that it wasn't the Cui Army's heavy cavalry,
可一看啊
they started to fight back.
这就来劲了
During the encounter,
这打着打着呀
I saw that Shu was running away.
我就看着这个阿恕要跑
I went after him.
我就去追
I was injured
这一不小心
due to my carelessness.
这不 就受伤了吗
Keep on bragging, won't you?
你就吹吧你
That's more than just a minor injury.
你那叫受了点伤吗
Listen,
我跟你们说
Bao has sustained serious injuries.
鲍大哥这回伤得可重了
You're not allowed to fight
你这以后一年半载的
for at least one year.
可不许跟人动武了
If not, even the deities can't save you when your internal organs are ruptured.
否则你内脏破损了
I can't fight?
这不让我打架
That's worse than
可比那个
forbidding me to drink!
不让我喝酒更难
You can't drink either.
那酒也是不能喝的
You...
你就
But you can have some peanuts.
你就只能吃点花生米了
Yeah, you should have more.
对 多吃点花生米
Have more peanuts.
多吃点花生米
Ear,
我说耳朵
you should hurry
你赶紧把人家桃子姑娘
and marry Taozi.
娶回家吧
If not,
免得她这一天
she'll interfere with our affairs all day long.
管东管西的
Precisely.
就是
You're wrong.
你这就说得不对了
Miss Taozi still can interfere with our affairs
这怎么桃子姑娘
after getting married to Ear.
就不能管东管西了
- Wait. - That's right.
不是
You didn't understand what Bao meant.
对呀
After Miss Taozi gets married to Ear, she'll only be minding his business.
桃子姑娘嫁给耳朵之后啊
- She doesn't have time for us. -  That's right.
没工夫管咱们呀
Miss Taozi is a righteous person.
桃子姑娘仗义
Even after she gets married,
到时候就算嫁人了
she'll still tend to us if we're injured.
我们受伤了
Touch wood.
天灵灵 地灵灵
I don't want to get injured.
我可不想受伤
Miss Taozi,
桃子姑娘
you don't need to worry about me.
我永远不用你管啊
Miss Taozi
我们
doesn't need to worry about us.
都不会让桃子姑娘操心
She only needs to worry about the number
桃子姑娘最应该操心的
of children she'll have with Ear.
是要和长耳生几个娃
Am I right?
对不对
- That's right! - Get yourself some babies!
没错 生娃 生娃
Taozi!
桃子
Miss Taozi, don't go!
别走啊 桃子姑娘
Taozi! How many children?
生几个
Miss Taozi!
桃子姑娘
- Go away! - What about a dozen?
起开
Taozi, don't listen to their nonsense.
桃子 你别听他们胡说
They're just spouting nonsense.
他们都是乱说的
Don't be angry.
你别生气
(Qingyun Temple) Greetings, Your Highness. I, Han Chang, am here.
臣 韩畅
General Han, spare the formalities.
韩将军免礼
Now,
如今
I'm just a cultivator.
我已经是清修之人
Please do not mention
从前的称谓
my past titles again.
以后就不要再提了
Yes.
是
Please have a seat.
快请坐吧
His Highness
太孙殿下
is doing well.
一切皆好
He was elated when he heard
听说臣要来见您
that I was going to see you.
十分欢喜
He wished that he could see you personally one day.
只盼着有一天
He must be much taller now.
他一定长高了许多吧
The situation in the capital is still chaotic.
京中形势复杂
If not,
不然
I would've brought him here secretly.
就悄悄带他来见您了
Lord Qin once promised me
溱王曾答应过我
that he would assist the great imperial grandson
一定会辅佐太孙
to ascend the throne.
继承大统
Even now, you still think
如今您仍然觉得
that Lord Qin is trustworthy?
溱王可信吗
I still think that he's trustworthy.
我仍觉得他可信
Although Lord Qin is trustworthy,
溱王可信
Lord Xin and Lord Qi have the intention of usurping the throne.
信王与齐王
Lord Xin is the eldest prince.
信王居长
Lord Qi is ranked second.
齐王嫡次
However, Lord Qin has rendered plenty of military merit.
溱王偏又功高勋重
His siblings are extremely jealous.
极招忌惮
Lord Xin is heartless and unfaithful.
信王是个薄情寡义之人
He's easily
这个人
irritable
冲动易怒
and ruthless.
行事狠毒
However, he's quite dense.
却又不太聪明
I could tell from the incident where he murdered his wife.
从他杀害结发妻子之事
I just hope
我只希望
that he could be imprisoned forever.
他这一辈子都被关着
Yes.
是
I will contact the old subordinates loyal to the late crown prince.
臣会联络
I'll make sure Lord Xin
不会让信王
stay imprisoned.
轻易被放出来
As for Lord Qi,
至于齐王
although he's trying his best to hide his intention,
他虽然极力掩饰
people can tell
但也能看出来
that he has his eyes on
他对储君之位
the crown prince's throne.
垂涎三尺
He's only
这个人
witty without possessing true intelligence.
只有小聪明
He'll give himself away eventually.
他迟早会露出马脚
When that happens, we can take him down
倒时候我们就对他
in one fell swoop.
一击而中
Yes.
是
She's here.
来啦
Miss Cui, please try the Zhenxi Army's special roasted lamb.
崔小姐
Thank you.
谢谢
Let me have a try.
我尝尝
- Let's eat. - It's delicious.
吃吃吃
Mister Shiqi.
十七郎
Yeah, right?
是吧
we've been hiding something from you all along.
有件事
What is it?
什么事啊
Did you drink in Fengying Pavilion without my permission again?
是不是又瞒着我
That's not it.
不是 不是 不是
Before this,
之前啊
I asked you
我不是找你
for some money so that
要过几次银子吗
we could drink in Fengying Pavilion.
说是去丰迎楼吃酒
Actually, that wasn't the case.
其实不是
We spent the money
我们把钱呀
on something else.
都花在别的地方了
Bao, you shouldn't say that.
鲍哥 你别这么说
You're making it as if
你这么一说
we spent the money
跟俺们把钱花到什么
on somewhere indecent.
见不得人的地方似的
That's right.
对对对
You guys spent the money
花钱还能花到
on somewhere indecent?
见不得人的地方
What kind of place?
那是什么地方
It's that place in Fengying Pavilion...
那丰迎楼的
Taozi, eat up.
桃子 你赶紧吃羊肉啊
Yeah, you should eat up.
对对对 吃羊肉 吃羊肉
Have some lamb.
吃羊肉 吃羊肉
What kind of place?
什么地方
I don't know.
十七郎
We spent that money to rescue a person.
我们花钱救了个人
That's right.
对对对
That's right. We rescued a person.
对对对 我们救了个人
No, we rescued two people.
不对 我们救了两个人
That's right. Two.
对对对 两个人
That's right.
对对对
We saved Madam Qin
救了芹娘子
and her daughter, Xi.
和她的女儿小喜儿
War has been going on for quite some time.
这世道不好 一直打仗
Madam Qin's husband
芹娘子的丈夫
was beaten to death because he couldn't return
借了皇庄的粮还不上
the grain borrowed from the imperial mansion.
这活活被打死了
Madam Qin couldn't repay his debt
那芹娘子是卖艺
even when she's a performer.
都没还清欠债呀
The troupe leader was forcing her to be a prostitute.
班主要逼她做暗娼
He even wanted to sell her daughter off, Xi.
还要卖了她的女儿
She's only four years old.
小喜儿才四岁
Can we stand for that?
能忍吗
Of course not!
不能忍
After our discussion,
我们一商量
we redeemed Madam Qin from the troupe.
就凑钱给芹娘子赎了身
We helped Madam Qin
我们把芹娘子啊
to settle down in Youde's hometown.
就安排在我赵二哥
And, we even made three straw huts for her.
还搭了三间茅草屋
It's in Zhao Village, Pangxiang Sanlichong,
就在沂州据县
Yizhou, Ju Prefecture.
庞乡三里冲赵家村
Sanlichong is a great place.
三里冲可是个好地方
There are mountains and rivers.
有山有河
There are also plenty of ducklings in the river.
那河里还有好多小鸭子
Ducklings.
小鸭子
That's right.
对啊
They can lay eggs too.
它就能下蛋
All those ducklings will breed new ducklings.
小鸭子又能孵小鸭子
Mister Shiqi,
十七郎
by then, we'll return to Laolan Pass together with you.
到时候咱们就一起呀
That's right.
对 对
Return to Laolan Pass!
都回牢兰关
Head to Sanlichong!
都去三里冲
Mister Shiqi,
十七郎
we already came to an agreement.
我们都商量好了
We'll retire from the military when we get old.
等以后老了 不打仗了
We'll move to Sanlichong from Laolan Pass.
我们呀
You can visit us
你要是闲了
when you're bored.
就来看我们吧
Come and visit us.
来看我们
Mister Shiqi,
十七郎
we've realized
你吹的牛
your bragging for you.
我们帮你圆了
16 mu of fertile land
十六亩良田
and four top-grade cows, we've already prepared them for you.
四头上等黄牛
We've prepared them for you.
对 都准备好了啊
If that's the case, I think...
既然如此 那就
All right. It's a deal!
好 一言为定
It's a deal!
一言为定
- Cheers!
干
♪There are 18 river bends in Laolan River♪
牢兰河水十八湾
♪The first river bend is Yinsong♪
第一湾就是那银松滩
♪The fish in Yinsong is fat and meaty♪
滩
♪But they can't compare to the girl opening the window♪
比不上那姑娘眸儿美
Yingzhou is a cold place.
营州苦寒
There are rarely any fireflies there.
萤火虫特别少
You're considered lucky if you can encounter one
每逢秋夕能遇到一只
during the eve of fall.
都稀罕得不得了
However,
可是
on the night I was born,
偏偏在我出生那晚
a firefly
从窗外
flew in from the window
飞进来一只萤火虫
and stopped on top of my swaddling clothes.
就停在我的襁褓边上
It was gleaming.
一闪一闪 荧荧发亮
That's why Mother
所以阿娘
gave me the nickname, Ying.
就给我起了这个乳名
So, that's how
原来你的名字
you got your name.
是这么来的
I got my name
我的名字呢
from Bureau of Imperial Clan.
是宗正寺给我取的
It has a positive meaning.
字面意思挺好
They hoped that I could be witty and intelligent.
希望我将来能够聪颖
That's why they named me Ni.
所以名为嶷
However,
但到底
I didn't have a nickname.
我也没有一个乳名
My nanny called me Shiqi since young.
乳母从小就叫我十七郎
Everyone started calling me that eventually.
所以叫着叫着
If so,
那我以后
I'll only call you Shiqi from now on.
都只叫你十七郎
I was so furious
你口口声声
when you addressed me as Lord Qin.
叫我溱王殿下的时候
My father knew that I liked fireflies since I was young.
小的时候啊
He always told me this:
就总是跟我说
"Ying,
阿萤
I'll catch a firefly for you.
我给你捉一只萤火虫
Promise me one thing after that, okay?"
你就答应我一件事情
He either made me read
或是让我背书
or write.
或是让我写字
But I always tricked him.
但我总是耍赖
I told him this:
我告诉他
"Father,
阿爹
one firefly isn't enough.
捉一只萤火虫可不行
You have to catch 100 fireflies for me
你要给我捉回来一百只
before I'll make you a promise."
我才答应你
But he was too busy.
但是阿爹实在是太忙了
He didn't have the time
他哪里有工夫
to catch them for me.
真的帮我去捉
Therefore,
所以
I've never witnessed
我从来也没有见过
how it looked like when 100 fireflies were together.
一百只萤火虫
But tonight,
但是今天晚上
I'm sure there are
这里肯定有
at least 100 fireflies here.
一百只萤火虫吧
Give me your hand.
伸手
Ying,
阿萤
I'll catch 100 fireflies for you.
我为你捉一百只萤火虫
Can you promise me one thing?
能不能答应我一件事
I won't.
我不会答应的
I won't agree to it
就算你捉一千只
no matter how many fireflies
一万只萤火虫给我
you catch for me.
我都不会答应
Tonight's a joyous occasion.
今天晚上这么快乐
Let's drop the topic,
就别提别的事情了
okay?
好吗
♪There are 18 river bends in Laolan River♪
牢兰河水十八湾
♪The first river bend is Yinsong♪
第一湾就是那银松滩
♪The fish in Yinsong is fat and meaty♪
银松滩里鱼儿肥
♪But they can't compare to the girl opening the window♪
比不上姑娘的眸儿美
♪There are 18 river bends in Laolan River♪
牢兰河水十八湾
That song
这首歌
is nice.
真好听
Yeah.
是啊
If only this moment
多希望这样的时光
could last longer.
可以长久一些
I hope it will last longer.
再长久一些
Ying,
阿萤
actually, I...
其实我
This is an emergency!
紧急军情
Jieshuo has captured Baishui Pass?
揭硕攻破了白水关
Where is Baishui Pass?
白水关是哪儿
Your Majesty,
陛下
Baishui Pass
白水关
is a key point in Lianzhou.
是廉州的紧要之地
It's the most important gateway
是我朝至北
to our north.
最要紧的门户
Yanzhou and Zhuozhou
白水关之后
lie beyond Baishui Pass.
是雁州 濯州
There's no defensible position there.
无险可守
They can only fend off our enemies near Mang River.
只能据茫河抗敌
Jieshuo's cavalry
揭硕的铁骑
can actually go straight for Shuozhou's inland.
甚至可以直入
Your Majesty,
陛下
how were they able to capture Baishui Pass?
这白水关是如何失守的
That's an important pass
那可是
for us to keep Jieshuo at bay.
据守揭硕的重要关隘
Cui Yi, General Pingliang,
平凉大将军崔倚
should have stationed his main army there.
本该有重兵在那儿驻守
According to the emergency report,
据急报
the defending general of Baishui Pass
白水关的守将
was convinced by Liu Chengfeng, Cui Yi's adopted son,
就是被崔倚的养子
to surrender to Jieshuo.
柳承锋劝降
Cities southward of Baishui Pass
白水关以南的城池
were filled with fire and smoke.
烽烟处处
They were trampled upon by Jieshuo's cavalry.
被揭硕的铁骑蹂躏践踏
We need a few more days
更详细的军报
before we could hear about the details.
还要再过几日
I heard
臣听闻早先几日
that a few days ago, Cui Yi left Luoyang
那崔倚亲自领兵
together with his army
离开泺阳
and headed northward.
一路向北
What does Cui Yi mean by that?
崔倚此举意欲何为啊
Since his adopted son was the one who captured Baishui Pass,
既然破白水关的
if Cui Yi
那崔倚
was colluding with Jieshuo all along,
倘若早就跟揭硕勾结
I'm afraid
那现在
our nation is in peril now.
恐怕山河危殆呀
Where's Lord Qin?
溱王呢
He wants to fight
用不着他的时候
whenever I don't need him.
成天惦记着打仗
But where has he gone to when I need him now?
现在他到哪儿去了
That brat!
这个逆子
He just has to make me mad, huh?
他就是想气死朕
Jun,
大哥
Father still sees you as his favorite son.
父皇心中还是偏疼你的
However, some officials
只不过近来朝中群臣
appeared out of nowhere
又蹦出来了
and demanded you to be severely punished.
说是对大哥要严惩
Putting you under house arrest wasn't enough.
光是幽禁还不够
They wanted Father to strip you of your title too.
要削了大哥的王爵
Father wasn't happy when he heard that.
父皇一听也不乐意
But it was inappropriate for him to defend you in public.
但是也不好
It's all Li Ni...
这都是李嶷在从中作
It's all his fault.
作梗
By the way, Jun,
对了 大哥
this time, Father
父皇这回
was truly irritated with Li Ni.
是真的恼了李嶷了
He even reprimanded him today.
今日还破口大骂了
He said not only did he leave the capital without an imperial edict,
说李嶷不奉旨就出京
but he also went
在回京的路上
to your imperial mansion,
还特意跑到大哥的皇庄
stole the grain there,
去抢了大哥的粮仓
and distributed them to the farmers.
分给了那些佃户
He went overboard!
欺人太甚
He's bent on going against me!
他就是跟我作对
He wants to embarrass me!
就是想削了我的颜面
How dare he...
他趁着我被幽禁的时候
How dare he rob my mansion
他连我的庄子
when I'm under house arrest?
他连我的庄子都敢抢
Father said
父皇说
he was expecting
他本来还指望着
Li Ni to fend off Jieshuo.
李嶷去打揭硕
But Cui Yi kept telling him
但崔倚一再上书
that he was near Shuozhou.
说他就在朔州附近
In the end, Father changed his mind and let Cui Yi fend off the invaders.
结果父皇一转念
He even said that he would send him to reclaim Luoyang
还说
after his return.
就让他去收复泺阳
In conclusion,
说来说去
he just owns the Zhenxi Army.
就是他手握镇西军
So what if he can fight a war?
他能打仗罢了嘛
We have no choice.
没办法呀
The Zhenxi Army
谁让镇西军
only listens to his command.
都只听他李嶷的呢
The Zhenxi Army belongs to the imperial court!
那是我们国朝的镇西军
It doesn't belong to him!
又不是他李嶷的
People neglected that fact before this
以前那是战时危局
because times were chaotic.
没有人管这些
Now that the world is at peace,
现在天下太平了
what gives him the right to command the Zhenxi Army?
他凭什么手握镇西军呢
Doesn't that give him
那他岂不是
the power to do whatever he wants?
想干什么就干什么了吗
That's right, Jun.
是啊 大哥
The officials have already criticized him.
朝中群臣也多有诟病
Father told him off too.
父皇也是嘀咕了好几次
But even so,
但是
he still retains power over the Zhenxi Army.
也削不了他的兵权啊
Father.
阿爹
Excellent.
好
I'm glad that you're safe.
平安就好
Let me take a look at you.
让阿爹看看
You're fine.
还好 还好
Luckily, you just lost some weight. You're not injured.
只是瘦了些 没受伤
Father, you've gotten slimmer too.
阿爹也瘦了
You look frailer too.
还憔悴了
I'm sure it was because you were worried about me
肯定是日夜行军
while having to command your army.
还担心我
When I received a letter from Taozi
接到桃子飞鸽传书
saying that Lord Qin had rescued you,
说溱王
to be honest, that was the only night
说实话 那一夜
I could sleep.
阿爹才敢闭上眼睛睡着
I was deeply worried about you
这一路上
from the start until the end.
阿爹真是心急如焚
Sorry for making you worried.
让阿爹担心了
Why hasn't Lord Qin entered our camp?
溱王怎么不进营啊
Is he afraid of
是惧怕
the Cui Army's might?
我们崔家军的军威啊
Father,
阿爹
Lord Qin sent me here
溱王是送女儿过来
to rendezvous with you.
跟您会合
He'll be leaving soon.
他马上就走了
Look at him.
你看看他那样子
He's not even sweating a bit.
只怕连根汗毛都没掉
How dare he say that he's making an effort
也好意思说
to rescue my daughter?
为了救我女儿奔忙
Father,
阿爹
he already took a huge risk by leaving the capital
他未奉诏就带兵出京
with his army without an imperial edict.
已经很冒险了
Tell his stupid father
叫他那糊涂的皇帝老爹
to chop off his head then.
把他脑袋砍了才好
Father!
阿爹
He's actually leaving, huh?
他真的就这么走了
He rescued you, you know?
人家救了你啊
Why didn't you send him off?
你都不去送送啊
Father, you just said
阿爹 您刚才还说呢
you wanted his stupid father
让人家糊涂老爹
to chop off his head.
把他脑袋砍了才好
That's a different matter.
那是一码事归一码事
He saved your life, you know?
人家还救了你的命
Why didn't you see him off?
你怎么不去送送啊
Forget it.
算了
There's no need for that.
没什么好送的
I told you already.
我就说
Everyone from the Li family is stupid.
他们李家
Father,
阿爹
whose side are you on now?
您现在到底向着谁啊
He's truly hopeless.
真是无可救药
He's hopeless.
无可救药
Reporting in!
报
Great General,
大将军
Jieshuo has captured Baishui Pass!
揭硕破白水关了
Father, do you remember
父皇 您可都记住了
what you should say about Cui Yi
尤其是关于崔倚
and Baishui Pass?
和白水关的那些话
You must refute Lord Qin
一定要驳斥溱王
and make him
让他无法
unable to speak up for Cui Yi.
替崔倚说情才是啊
Don't worry.
放心吧
It's not that long.
就这么两句话
I can remember that.
朕还是能记住的
If so, I shall take my leave.
那儿臣先告退
His Highness has arrived.
殿下到了
Greetings, Father.
儿臣拜见父皇
So, you still remember that this is your home?
你还知道回来啊
I did go a little further than I expected for my hunt.
此番围猎
You said you went on a hunt, huh?
你口口声声围猎
If so, why were you
怎么会围猎到
at your brother's imperial mansion?
你大哥的庄子上去了
And, you even robbed
而且把你大哥
his mansion
庄子上的粮食
of food.
都给抢了
Father, I was planning to ask you why
儿臣正想问父皇
you said you wanted to release Lord Xin from house arrest
为何在朝中与百官言道
on the imperial court.
想要解除信王的禁足
You want to release him after such a short period?
这才幽禁没有多久
You're abusing your power here.
如此徇私枉法
The people will think ill of you.
天下如何看待
Don't tell me what to do here.
别在这儿指手画脚
You're the same as those civil officials.
跟那些文官一个腔调
You say that I'm abusing my power here?
口口声声徇私枉法
Who's the emperor here?
到底我是皇帝
You? Or me?
还是你是皇帝呀
Father, you shouldn't say something like that.
父皇不应该说这种话
Don't try to lecture me.
别在这里教训朕
I dare not do so.
儿臣不敢
You dare not do so?
不敢
But you're bold enough to do all the things, aren't you?
你敢的事可多了
Cui Yi left Luoyang together with his army.
崔倚带兵离开了岽都
I heard that his daughter
听说他女儿
had just returned to Luoyang.
刚刚回到了泺阳
Not many troops were stationed there.
带着不多的人留守
Since you're back,
你既然回来了
you should reclaim Luoyang
就领着镇西军
together with the Zhenxi Army.
去收复泺阳吧
Father.
父皇
Cui Yi is fending off Jieshuo at the North.
崔倚在北上迎击揭硕
But now, you're ordering me to attack Luoyang?
父皇却命我去攻泺阳
What if Cui Yi hears about this?
若崔倚知道后方如此
Father, aren't you afraid that this news will affect their morale?
父皇难道就不怕
Luoyang is imperial court's capital.
泺阳是朝廷的岽都
Cui Yi has occupied it shamelessly for a long time.
崔倚厚颜无耻占据已久
Shouldn't we attack him while he least expects it and reclaim it?
难道不应该攻其不备
I wonder what's on your mind.
你不知道是怎么想的
You love to fight, right?
成天惦记着打仗
Now I'm sending you to fight them.
现在让你去打仗
But you're defying my orders here.
却又抗旨
Father,
父皇
Cui Yi is fending off the invaders at the frontline.
崔倚在前线抗战
We can't attack him from the back.
我们不能乱他后方
The military report already stated the reason
白水关到底是怎么丢的
why Baishui Pass was captured.
军报上写得清清楚楚
Cui Yi's son was the one who convinced them to surrender.
崔倚的儿子跑去劝降
The defending general spared him on account
守城之将念及旧情
of their past ties.
不忍杀他
But him?
他倒好
He killed the defending general
带着揭硕的死士
together with Jieshuo.
把守将给杀了
Cui Yi raised a traitorous son
崔倚养出这样的儿子
who betrayed his nation.
通敌卖国
Everyone in the imperial court
朝中的群臣
wants him to be punished.
纷纷都说要治他的罪
Prime Minister Gu was the one who advised me
那是顾相劝我
to let him atone for his sin by rendering merit.
让崔倚将功赎罪
Father,
父皇
Cui Yi severed his ties with his adopted son, Liu Chengfeng, long ago.
崔倚与他的养子柳承锋
Because Liu Chengfeng colluded with Jieshuo.
只因柳承锋勾结揭硕
The Cui family and Jieshuo are sworn enemies.
崔家与揭硕
Of all the families to doubt,
父皇就算怀疑谁
the Cui family shouldn't be the one you doubt.
都不应该怀疑崔家
Lord Qin,
溱王
you've truly
你真是让朕
disappointed me.
太失望了
Let me ask you this.
那么朕现在问你
My order is for you to reclaim Luoyang with the Zhenxi Army.
领镇西军收复岽都
Will you
你遵旨
follow my order or not?
还是不遵旨
I will not.
儿臣不遵旨
Father, please permit me
儿臣请旨
to return to Laolan Pass.
回牢兰关戍边
Lord Qi
镇西军
will take command of the Zhenxi Army for now.
暂交齐王代管
You can return to your residence
你就先回府
and reflect upon your actions.
好好闭门思过去吧
Yes, Father.
是
I shall take my leave.
儿臣告退
Shiqi!
十七郎
What are you doing here?
你怎么来了
Don't mention that.
别提了
His Majesty allowed Lord Qi
今天在朝中
to take command of the Zhenxi Army for now during morning court.
陛下将镇西军
Lord Qi ordered me and Father to leave the capital immediately.
齐王命我和父亲
Father will head to Lingzhou
父亲前往凌州
while I'll head to Bizhou.
我前往泌州
Lord Qi has premeditated this for a long time.
齐王所为
That day, Father was abnormally eloquent
那日父皇
when he ordered me
想命我收复岽都
to reclaim Luoyang.
言辞厉害
Father can never think of something like that.
父皇说不出来那样的话
I assume Lord Qi was the one who told him what to say.
想必
He's doing so
他这么做
to divide
就是想将你身边的人
our forces
一一调开
and segregate the Zhenxi Army.
然后分化我们镇西军
I'm unhappy with life in the capital.
我在这京中十分不快
We've been spending time ever since I went to Laolan Pass
自十几岁去了牢兰关
while I was a teenager.
咱们就在一起
You understand my feelings too.
你也明白我心里
I think there's no point in living in the imperial residence.
觉得京都王府
The palace
而皇宫
is even worse.
更是没有意思
But Shiqi,
可是十七郎
none of us can return to Laolan Pass now.
咱们都回不去牢兰关了
Ying always wanted me to understand
阿萤一心想让我明白
that both Lord Xin
信王
and Lord Qi
齐王
were untrustworthy.
非可信之人
She said they shouldn't be the ones ruling the world.
说天下
She wants me to be the crown prince.
她想让我当这个太子
But I promised Consort Xiao
可我答应过萧妃娘娘
that I would assist the great imperial grandson.
一定要辅佐太孙
Ying and I
我与阿萤
were deeply in love.
本是两情相悦
However, we grew estranged
因为这样的事
because of this issue.
几乎闹到生分
Actually, I understand
其实她说的话
where she's coming from.
我心里都明白
However, there's something
只是我有句话
I haven't told her yet.
一直未同她说
Shiqi,
十七郎
what exactly are you worried about?
你到底在担忧什么呢
That's right.
是啊
I'm indeed worried about something.
我心中有所顾虑
Sun Jing is dead.
孙靖已死
The world is at peace.
天下平定
Where should the Zhenxi Army
咱们镇西军
go from here?
该何去何从
Where should the Cui Army
而崔家军
If I do become the crown prince,
如果我当了太子
will the imperial court be able to agree
朝中会容忍太子妃
that the crown princess owns the Cui Army?
手握崔家军吗
Even if I do become the crown prince,
如果我当了太子
Cui Yi will never
崔倚也不会
hand the Cui Army to me.
把手中的崔家军交给我
That day,
那日
Father ordered me to reclaim Luoyang.
父皇命我收复岽都
I rejected him.
被我拒绝了
He handed the Zhenxi Army to Lord Qi out of spite.
他一气之下
It's because I didn't want to engage Ying in battle.
是因为我不想与阿萤
But once I become the crown prince,
但一旦我成为了储君
I have no choice
就不得不由我
but to suppress the Cui Army myself.
亲自去打压崔家军了
400,
四百
500,
五百
600.
六百
Where is he?
人呢
Taozi!
桃子
You scared me.
你吓死我了你
Here you go.
给你
What is it?
什么呀
That's a lot of money.
这么多银钱
These are my savings.
这都是我平日攒下来的
I forgot to give it to you last time
上一次匆匆忙忙
as I was in a rush.
就忘记给你了
This is a lot of money.
这么多银钱
Why are you giving it to me?
给我干吗
Keep it for me first.
你先替我拿着
We can use it in the future.
等将来
In the future, I...
将来
Why must I keep it for you?
干吗要我替你拿着
What do you mean by that?
什么将来
I don't understand.
听不懂
Taozi,
桃子
I thought you already said yes to me last time.
你上回
But you...
这
Silly guy.
傻子
I was just teasing you.
我逗你的呀
You fell for it so easily.
这么容易就上当
You scared me.
吓死我了
All right.
好了
I'll keep this money
这些银钱呢
on your behalf.
我替你好好收着
In the future,
以后啊
I'll keep
我的饷银
my money together with it too.
也跟它放在一起
Maybe
说不定
we can buy some land
之后我们可以买几亩田
or open a shop in the future.
或者置个铺子也好啊
Okay.
好
Whatever you say.
你说什么就是什么
You have to be more alert in the future.
以后你可得当心啊
You mustn't
不能这么容易
be duped that easily.
就被骗了啊
Okay.
好
Let's go then.
那我们走吧
I'll bring you around Xichang.
我带你逛逛西长京
Let's go.
走吧
Taozi.
桃子
Over here. This side is busier.
这边 这边热闹
Mister Shiqi!
十七郎 十七郎
Wake up!
快起来 快起来
Mister Shiqi, wake up!
醒醒 醒醒 十七郎
What's the matter?
怎么了
I have good news for you.
告诉你个好消息
Miss Cui is here.
崔小姐来了
What?
什么
Miss Cui has arrived at Xichang.
崔小姐到西长京来了
Taozi is here too.
桃子也来了
Ear is meeting up with Taozi as we speak.
耳朵现在去见桃子了
I heard
听说
that Miss Cui came here just to seek an audience with His Majesty.
崔小姐这次来
Seeking an audience with His Majesty?
觐见陛下
That's what I heard from Miss Taozi.
是啊 桃子姑娘说的
She said
她说呀
Miss Cui came here to seek an audience with His Majesty
这次崔小姐来
on Great General Cui's behalf.
来觐见陛下的
Therefore, she hopes
所以说啊
that she can seek an audience with His Majesty during a court session.
希望能在大朝之日
She's trying to drive me crazy here.
她这是想气死我
Mister Shiqi,
十七郎
you shouldn't say that.
你这就不对了
Although she's here to see His Majesty,
虽说是觐见陛下
it's likely that she's here to see you.
但八成还是想见见你
You'll break her heart
你这么说
if you say that.
不是伤人心吗
You don't understand.
你不懂
What do you mean?
我不懂
Teach me then.
那你教教我
I'm all ears.
说来听听
The imperial court is fearful of the Cui family.
朝中忌惮崔家
It's a controversial topic.
议论纷纷
All of them are like boiling pots filled with oil.
都像是煮沸的油锅子
It'll explode as long as there's a single drop of water.
但凡沾点水星子都得炸
And now, she's adding fuel to the flame.
她还来火上烧油
Besides, she said she would seek an audience with His Majesty
再说了
on Great General Cui's behalf.
觐见陛下
That's beyond comprehension.
匪夷所思
Even Great General cannot enter the capital without an imperial edict.
大将军不奉诏
Moreover,
更何况她还是
she's just his daughter.
大将军的女儿
How could she attend a court session?
怎么能上朝堂呢
The civil officials
朝中那些文官
will drown her with their words.
唾沫星子都能喷死她
I don't understand at all.
我就搞不明白了
Why does it sound like
你这话怎么听
you're worried about Miss Cui?
都像是在担心崔小姐
She's witty and intelligent.
她主意大着呢
I don't need to worry about her.
我为什么要担心她
Since she's already here,
那人家都来了
why don't you go and see her?
要不要先去见见她
No, I won't.
不见
Are you sure?
真的不见
I won't.
不去 不去
Are you sure about this?
真不去
(Go Classics) The Ministry of Rites
这个礼部啊
has been arguing among themselves for the past few days.
吵嚷这么些天
Even now, there's no result.
什么结果都没吵出来
I wonder when
真不知道什么时候
you can see His Majesty.
你才能去觐见陛下
Young Lady,
小姐
do you wish to see Lord Qin?
你想不想去见溱王
Lord Qin is something else.
这个溱王也真是的
You've already been here for a few days.
你都已经来了几天了
But he didn't even visit you.
他都不说过来看看你
Last time, he rushed all the way there just to rescue you.
上回
After that,
后来
he even sent you back to Great General.
还把你送回了
Back then, I thought
我当时还想
that he was pretty nice to you.
这个人对我们家小姐
It's only been a few days,
这才几天啊
yet he's treating you
怎么突然
like a stranger again.
又像陌路人一样了
Have you met Xie Chang'er?
你去见过谢长耳了
Of course I have.
当然见过了
If so,
那
what has he told you?
他都跟你说些什么呀
Nothing much.
也没说些什么
It wasn't anything important.
不是什么要紧的话
If so, I assume Lord Qin
那估计溱王
has nothing important
也没什么要紧的话
to tell me.
要跟我说
That's why he's not visiting me.
所以就不见了
That's not the case.
才不是这样呢
Although there was nothing important he wanted to say,
虽说是
you see,
但是你看啊
Ear and I
我跟耳朵呢
went to see an acrobatic performance.
一起去看了杂耍
We even shopped around
我们还去铺子里
in the city.
买了好多好多东西呢
Even if
那就算是
there's nothing important to say,
没有什么要紧的事
we're happy
只要我们两个人
when we get
在街上走着
to take a walk together.
那心里也是高兴的
Why are you flustered when Lord Qin
溱王不来见我
isn't visiting me?
你怎么这么着急啊
I'm not flustered.
我不是着急
I'm just worried about you.
我那是担心你
Worried about me?
担心我
I was just thinking
我是想着
that you might want to see Lord Qin.
你会不会想要见溱王吗
Could it be...
会不会
Could it be that you wish to see someone else?
还是你想见谁啊
That's not true.
我不想
What a lousy whistle.
这个破哨子
Taozi!
桃子
What took you so long?
这么久才来 慢死了
I rushed here when I heard the whistle.
我听到哨子就赶过来了
I was late because it was too far away.
但是太远了
Did you say Lord Qin was treating you guys to a drink
你说
at Fengying Pavilion?
请你们喝酒
That's right.
是啊
If so, did he say
那他有没有说
that he would visit Young Lady?
要来见我们家小姐啊
No.
没有
What's wrong with him?
这个人怎么回事
Since he's treating you guys to a drink,
他有工夫请你们喝酒
that means he's not busy.
那说明他不忙嘛
If he's not busy,
他不忙为什么不来
why didn't he visit Young Lady?
见我们家小姐
Bao asked him the same question.
这个老鲍也问他了
But Mister Shiqi acted as if
但十七郎那会儿
he didn't hear him.
就跟没听到似的
Why did they
这两个冤家
get into a quarrel again?
怎么又闹上别扭了
Yeah.
是啊
They seemed
你看上次
harmonious
救完崔小姐以后
on their way back after Mister Shiqi saved Miss Cui.
他们俩回来路上
They didn't argue
一路上既没有吵架
or get into a fight.
也没有打架
They were courteous to each other.
感觉客客气气的
Silly guy, what do you know?
你个傻东西知道什么呀
It's only troublesome when they don't argue
这既不吵架也不打架
or get into a fight.
那才麻烦呢
This won't do.
不行
We have to think of something.
咱们得好好想个法子
What do you mean?
想什么法子
Since
既然
he's not willing to see her,
他不肯去找她
and she's not willing to see him,
她也不肯去找他
one of them
那这两个人当中
has to
必须得先有一个人
take the first step somehow.
迈出第一步
Wait, come again?
不是 什么他呀她的
I'm confused.
我都听糊涂了
Got it.
有了
Let's buy some dried fruits.
咱们买干果去
What's with that response?
啊什么啊
Come on.
走了走了走了
Hurry up.
快点
I heard that Fengying Pavilion's the best restaurant in the capital.
早听说丰迎楼
It does live up to its name.
果真名不虚传
The food here is great.
饭好吃
The liquor is great.
酒也好喝
Although it's great,
酒是好酒
it's a shame
可惜鲍大哥
that Bao can't take alcohol now.
现在不能喝酒呢
Where's Bao?
鲍大哥呢
He said he was going to take a leak.
刚说方便一下
Don't tell me
难道
he fell into the loo?
掉茅厕去了
Since he said that,
人家说方便
I'm sure he went to the loo.
就是去茅厕了
Why did you say he fell into the loo?
你为什么说掉茅厕里了
One can only take a leak
这方便方便
in a loo.
不去茅厕
Is he going to somewhere else?
难道还能去别处啊
But of course.
那当然了
What about this?
这样
Let's make a bet.
咱们打个赌
Let's play a game.
比划拳
The winner
谁要赢了
will drink
就喝酒
while the loser has to find Bao and see if he has fallen into the loo.
谁要输了就去找老鲍
All right.
好
Let's do it!
玩一把 玩一把
Come on!
来 来
My good brothers!
兄弟好啊
Three stars!
三星照啊
Five leaders!
五魁首啊
Six prosperity!
六六顺啊
Four wealth!
四喜财呀
My good brothers!
兄弟好啊
Six prosperity!
六六顺啊
Five leaders!
五魁首啊
Eight horses!
八匹马啊
I won!
我赢了
Mister Shiqi, guess who's in the next room?
十七郎
My turn.
我来我来
- Again! - Let me take a bite.
在来 在吃口菜
My good brothers!
兄弟好呀
Seven wonders!
七个巧呀
Six prosperity!
六六顺呀
Eight horses!
八匹马呀
Three stars!
三星照啊
He lost!
大哥输了
I lost.
我输了
Mister Shiqi,
十七郎
don't you wish to check it out?
你就不想去看看
Fine.
行
Anyway, I've already notified you.
反正我跟你说了
It's your business whether you go or not.
你不去是你的事
Come! Give it a try!
大哥 来来来
Let's do it.
给我们打个样
Let's continue.
接着来 来
My good brothers!
兄弟好啊
One star!
一星定啊
Five leaders!
五魁首啊
Seven wonders!
七个巧啊
Taozi,
桃子
(Wolong Dried Fruits Store) why did you buy so many dried fruits?
你买这么多干果
Young Lady loves them.
小姐喜欢吃这个
I intend to move her
我打算用这个干果
with these dried fruits.
感动她
Bao,
老鲍
Taozi instructed us to forbid you from drinking
桃子可是千叮咛万嘱咐
in the next year.
不能喝酒
Put it down.
放下
Fine.
不喝就不喝嘛
Bao, get us some peanuts.
鲍哥 来点你的花生米
- Yeah. - That's right.
有啊 对啊
That's right, Bao.
对呀 鲍哥
I have plenty of peanuts.
花生米有啊
Here you go.
这不是
Give it to me.
拿来
Catch.
拿着
Eat up.
来 吃
What is this?
啥呀这
Mister Shiqi, I'll give you two.
十七郎 你俩
Bao is so stingy.
这老鲍太抠了吧
You're so stingy.
你太抠门了
Take it or leave it.
爱吃不吃你们
This liquor is pretty strong.
这酒确实有些上头
I need to take a leak.
我出去方便方便
Mister Shiqi, take your time.
十七郎 你慢点
Let's continue.
咱们继续 咱们继续
Six six!
六个六啊
My good brothers!
兄弟好啊
Six prosperity!
六六顺啊
Come here.
过来 过来 过来
Place your bets.
买定离手啊
Let's make a bet
咱们就赌
whether Mister Shiqi will check out the next room or not.
十七郎去还是不去
Place your bets.
下注吧
I think he'll surely check it out.
我觉得呀
All right.
好
Ten wen!
押十文
He'll go, ten wen!
去 十文
Anyone else?
还有谁
He won't go, all-in!
我全押 他不去
He has to go!
他必须去
All right!
好
20 wen!
二十文
He won't go, 20 wen!
二十文 不去
All right. He won't go, huh? It's a deal.
好 不去
No sore losers here, all right?
愿赌服输
- All right!
愿赌服输 好
We can't hear anything.
啥也听不见啊这
If only Ear was here.
要耳朵在就好了啊
Young Lady.
小姐
Lord Qin bought your favorite dried fruits
溱王特意买了
to deliver them to you.
让我拿过来的
Really?
是吗
Yeah.
是啊
Young Lady,
小姐
you might not know,
你可是不知道
but one has to queue for eons before they can buy
这个干果
these dried fruits.
才能买到的
Let me try them.
拿来我尝尝
He's back.
回来了
Mister Shiqi,
十七郎
did you check out the room?
你进隔壁看没有啊
Did you? You didn't, right?
进了吗
Did you enter the room?
没进吧
I didn't.
没进
Guys, accept your losses.
愿赌服输
Youde, here you go.
老二 接着
Youdao, here.
老四 来
Mister Shiqi,
这 十七郎
why didn't you enter the room?
你咋不进去呢
I lost so much money because of you.
你害得俺输了好多钱
You must have no idea.
这你就不知道了吧
Mister Shiqi was the best scout
十七郎是军中
we had.
最好的斥候
I'm sure he found out
他肯定发现啊
that there were two burly men
隔壁是两个抠脚大汉
instead of Miss Cui in the next room.
发现不是崔小姐
That's why he didn't fall for it.
所以就不上当
That's right.
对
There were three people.
是三个
Three people?
三个
But I only saw two people.
我怎么看见是两个呢
They ordered liquor and food enough for two.
他们点的酒水 饭食
They only had two pairs of chopsticks in the room.
连筷子
You...
你
How did you find out
你怎么就
that there were three people?
发现是三个呢
One of them is downstairs.
还有一个在楼下
He just came upstairs.
刚刚上来
They are hemp traders.
他们都是贩纻麻的商人
They just arrived from Xingzhou.
刚从兴州过来
They have plenty of money.
身上的银钱有很多
The other guy went to exchange his currency.
落单那个是去换钱了
He didn't want to eat at Fengying Pavilion.
本来不想来迎丰楼吃饭
He still came here eventually.
后来想想还是来了
That's why the waiter
所以茶博士
prepared another set of bowl and chopsticks for them.
又多准备了一副碗筷
Mister Shiqi is amazing indeed.
还是十七郎厉害呀
I'm impressed.
佩服 佩服
I told you already.
我就说嘛
Although Mister Shiqi didn't enter the room,
十七郎虽然没进去
he could definitely
但他肯定会把隔壁
figure out
是什么人 什么身份
who was in the next room.
弄得清清楚楚
You weren't willing to believe me.
你们还不服气
You just had to make the bet.
偏要跟我赌
Now, you've lost.
输了吧
Pay up!
给钱
We'll pay up.
给钱 给钱 给钱
- This is mine. - I've lost ten wen again.
这是我的
Young Lady,
我又输了十文
since Lord Qin bought these dried fruits for you especially,
小姐
don't you think
咱们是不是
we should buy him something
也应该送他点什么
in return?
表示一下感谢
They're pretty nice.
确实挺好吃的
At least you didn't queue in vain.
不枉你排队排了那么久
How did you know
你怎么知道
that Lord Qin didn't buy these dried fruits?
这个干果不是溱王买的
You saw through at once, huh?
这一眼就被你识破
I guess Lord Qin wouldn't fall for it too.
看来八成也骗不到溱王
Fall for what?
骗他什么
Xie Chang'er brought some of these
就是这个干果
back to him too.
谢长耳也带了一份回去
We intended to say
本来我俩都商量好了
that you were the one
就说这个干果
who bought these for him.
是你给他买的
But now,
这下可好了
I don't think he'll fall for it.
他八成也是骗不到
Here.
来
The buyer should finish it then.
那就谁买的谁吃
I queued for a long time just to buy them.
真的排了很久的队的
They're pretty good.
是挺好吃的
It must've been tough.
辛苦你了
Fine, I'll finish them myself.
我自己吃
Here. Let me offer you a toast.
来
Jun,
大哥
I'm sure you know this too.
你又不是不知道
Although Father put me in charge of the Zhenxi Army temporarily,
父皇虽然让我
Pei Xian and his son
但是那裴氏父子
would never obey my orders.
怎肯听我的呢
My position
我这代管
is just for show.
不过是个虚职罢了
You're 100 times better
比起我来
than me.
天天被关在这府上
I'm stuck here for an unknown period.
你强百倍吧
Jun, you shouldn't be so dejected.
大哥何必泄气呢
Right now, there's an opportunity for you
眼下刚好有个机会
for you to make a plea in front of Father.
可以向父皇求情
What opportunity?
什么机会
Mother's death anniversary is arriving.
母后的忌辰快到了
Father will definitely go easy on you
看在已逝母后的情分上
on account of our late mother.
父皇肯定会心软
You're right.
对呀
Mother's death anniversary is nearing.
母后的忌辰快到了
If so, I'll submit a fold to Father
那我要亲自给父皇上书
to tell him about it.
来诉说此情
Maybe Father
也许父皇能看在
will release me
母后的分儿上
on account of Mother.
把我给放了
Jun, don't worry.
大哥放心吧
I'll definitely do my best to make a plea on your behalf
臣弟定然会
in front of Father.
替大哥求情的